KAREN WAGGONER



Professional Summary

Integrity-driven data analyst that enjoys cleaning data. Previous experience in language development and education, including teaching, training, finance, communications, and projects. Skilled in collaborating and communicating internationally. To refresh my skill set, after a parenting career break, I have completed courses in spreadsheets, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Python, and R; and am ready to continue my career on a full time basis.

Skills

Excel & Google Sheets: Cleaning | Filters | Functions | Formulas | VLOOKUP | Nested IF Statements | Pivot Tables | Visualization

SQL: Cleaning | Common Table Expressions | Group By Aggregates | Window Functions | Subqueries | Ranking | Table Joins

Tableau: Parameters | Charts | KPIs | Dashboard

Python: Pandas | Matplotlib

Education

BA in MATHEMATICS with a minor in BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION – University of West Georgia – Carrollton, GA

Spreadsheet Fund. (15 hrs), SQL Fund. (22 hrs), Tableau Fund. (in progress), Intermediate Python, Intro to R – DataCamp

Google Data Analytics Certificate – Coursera

Projects

BANKING PRE-POST ANALYSIS - SQL Project - Examined the World Bank's IDA COVID project financing using SQL.

RESTAURANT INSIGHTS – <u>SQL Project</u> – Built **queries** for insights into customer patterns, spending, and favorites.

EDUCATION ANALYSIS - Tableau Project - Created a dashboard for the superintendent, delivering insights about student success.

FOOD DELIVERY MARKETING – <u>Google Sheets Project</u> – Found business opportunities and proposed actions to optimize campaigns.

YARN INSIGHTS – Google Sheets Project – Collected, cleaned, and visualized data to create a **slide deck** delivering project yarn insights.

Experience

DATA ANALYST & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT - Freelance - Villa Rica, GA

2022 - present

- Case Sampling Analyst, Disaster Finance (American Red Cross Volunteer) Examine financial assistance cases, verify the eligibility of clients to ensure compliance with internal policies, and report non-compliant ones using Excel
- Earned a Google **Data Analytics** Certificate, finished 25+ courses with Datacamp, and completed 5 personal projects using spreadsheets, SQL, and Tableau

HOMESCHOOL TEACHER - Career Break - Villa Rica, GA

2010 - 2022

 Researched and customized curriculum, assessed learning styles, taught K-5th (all subjects), monitored progress, analyzed test scores, managed workflows, and provided support and accommodations for neurodiversity • **Communicated** specific feedback to clients by **assessing** students' performance, **monitoring** progress, and identifying areas for language improvement for 1,828 students, while teaching remotely and maintaining an average review rating of 5.0/5.0

LANGUAGE SPECIALIST - SIL International - Vietnam

2006 - 2010

- **Collaborated** with Save the Children Vietnam by conducting a primer writing workshop for rural teachers, that supported the goals of the Ministry of Education and Training for mother tongue-based, bilingual education within minority areas
- Studied language, **researched** culture, and **partnered** with mother-tongue speakers to craft, test, document, and revise stories to initiate a story-set that was natural sounding, orally reproducible, and accurate

AREA COMMUNICATIONS ASSISTANT – SIL International – Philippines

2005-2006

- Informed stakeholders by using Plone to post data and reports to the corporate intranet during the international conference, giving worldwide regional offices access to the latest discussions and policy decisions
- Improved the searchability of the data management system, by uploading and tagging unstructured data, allowing communication teams to quickly and easily locate data for media projects

FINANCE COORDINATOR - SIL International - China

2002-2005

- Researched the need for a future conference site by analyzing the member growth rate, resulting in the continuity of the entire
 group being housed in one location
- Reconciled the monthly accounts while monitoring provincial cash custodians in compliance with organizational financial policies
- Presented project data by meeting with potential stakeholder groups, resulting in \$70,000+ raised in annual funds